SOMETHING ABOUT ME

Computer Science engineer with more than 22 years of experience in Telecommunications technology, Software Development and Service Engineering world.

Being a tech-driven, software-centric, and service engineering minded **Technical Leader**, I have a clear orientation towards Technology Leadership, Delivery Ownership, and Product Development. I consider myself a very proactive person, always looking for simplicity and resilience in all our features / capabilities that can avoid daily problems in our big scale platforms.

Strong technical background in architecting / automating and optimizing mission critical deployments over big data infrastructure. Share knowledge and experience in Architecture and DevOps areas.Proven management and coordination skills. Part of the Ericsson Leadership

Working in the last years at Telefónica, a world leading telecommunication company with succesful mobile and fixed services, as Technical Leader and DevOps Architect. In my current position, our platform provides authentication, authorization, unified APIs and big data capabilities. Deployed in Azure with Kubernetes using AKS (some time ago in AWS with kops) we put together a wide range of technologies like Python + Terraform, traefik, kafka, PostgreSQL, kong, Prometheus, ElasticSearch, fluentd, fluent-bit, Kibana, Grafana or spark4k8s to achieve our

Top Experiences: Platform Development & Engineering, Device Configuration, CS Core, Packet Core, High Performing teams leadership, Business Strategy Development, People Coaching and Management, Engineering Management, Security and Compliance, Tech Strategy and Methodologies.

Tech Experience: DevOps, Cloud, Data Engineering, Microservices, Event-driven Architectures, REST APIs, NGIN, IMS, Device Configuration (TR69).

Domains Experience: Telco, Toll, Fleet Management and Video Surveillance.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate in Education Universidad de Valladolid

Master in development of Inter/Intranet Apps (Java & J2EE)

Degree in Computer Science 1996 - 2000 Universidad de Valladolid

Graduate in Computer Science (Physical Systems) 1992 - 1996

EXPERIENCES

Lead Platform Engineering, Telefonica Kernel

Evolving the Telefonica Kernel Platform to the next-gen telco open architecture.

- Platform Architecture and Design. IaaC
- Continuous Integration development and support
- · Continuous Delivery for integration environments
- Developers & QnA portals development and support
- Service Engineering in the production environments. Support Level 3.
- · Product development
- · Engineering Leadership

Lead Service Engineering, Telefonica Kernel Nov 2018 - Nov 2021

Working in the 4th platform (4P) as Service Engineering Lead, improving the observability and

- · Multi cloud deployment
- · Single point of view for cloud and service metrics
- Log systems in elastic big scale platforms
- · Unified visibility for cloud and services logs
- · Alarms based in anomaly detections
- Improve resilience in our Infrastructure as Code

Operational Business Integration Technical Leader, Tuenti Jan 2017 - Jul 2018

Leading the services integration in the Operational Business of the company.

- · VoIP Product development
- · Design and Development of NGIN integration services



David Gallegos Pajares

- ✓ dgalpaj@gmail.com
- www.david.gallegos.com
- Chat in Telegram
- in Connect in Linkedin
- Follow me on Github
- Follow me on Twitter
- </>
 dgalpaj
- Download my resume in PDF

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English (Professional)

OTHER HOBBIES

Travelling (keep calm & open mind) Handball (hard team work)

Motorbikes (speed)

Nov 2021 - Present

Guitar player (resilience & patience)

- · Integration plan development
- · API design and validation
- Communications project leadership

Telco Engineering Team Leader, TUgo

Team Leader at TUgo (Telefónica) managing the Telco Engineering team providing voice and message services.

- Team responsability around the E2E deliverables life cycle, including QA, Deployment and Operation stages.
- Team activity around a set of Telco B2C products, consisting on Mobile apps and Backend
- · Technical reference and hands-on resource on complex operational issues or project blockers.
- · Multi-location (Spain & Israel) project
- Implemented an Agile team way-of-working based on Scrum methodology
- Focus on people development for individual and collective profesional growth.



Oct 2010 - Nov 2015

Nov 2015 - Jan 2017

Lead Architect Engineer, CS/PS Core Multiactivation at Ericsson.

- E2E Project delivery from pre-sales to acceptance
- Areas of responsibility, Network Management, Service Assurance, Service Fulfillment
- Provisioning design towards the core nodes (HLR, FNR, AUC), the IMS nodes (DNS, HSS, PGM, BWAS, etc.) and the UDC nodes (CUDB, HLR-FE, HSS-FE, etc.)
- · Ericsson Multi Activation (EMA)
- Automatic Device Configuration (ADC)
- Ericsson remote device management (ERDM)
- SF Telcordia and Conceptwave portfolio knowledge
- MARC (Modem Automatic Remote Configuration) system at Telefónica LATAM (ALU HNM5580 ACS TR069 integration with SIGRES).



Sep 2007 - Sep 2010

R&D Engineer for Telefonica CCDO (Future Comms Area) at the End Customer Device

- · Analisys and evaluation of remote configuration capabilities in new lan line modem prototipes for integration in Telefonica's broadband service
- Design and development of end-to-end technical solution for the automatic remote
- Product leadership at Telefónica LATAM (Chile, Argentina, Peru, Colombia and Brasil)
- Lead development and deployment of internal projects and POCs.



Jan 2000 - Sep 2007

 $Providing \ solution \ design, \ development, \ integration, \ testing \ and \ Life \ Cycle \ Management \ in \ the$ Final User Applications department of Telefónica I+D.

- · Lead and implement multiple proofs of concept finally converted in products
- Technology prospection in the device remote configuration domain
- · Working in different patents based in the proofs of concept
- Technology evangelist inside the company, teacher and speaker in different events across the world



Project Leader

Jan 1999 - Jan 2000

Technical leader for small fleets. Full software lifecycle management in the vehicle tracking solutions

- Integration of GIS systems in our platform
- Performance optimization for the database integration
- · Full architecture refactorization of the small fleets product
- Provide automatized process for the release management of the product: QA & Integration
- Interfaz definition for the communication with on boarding devices
- Development of the next-gen of product gui

Software Engineer

Jan 1998 - Jan 1999

Development and deployment of applications at the traffic and toll control department.

- Design of anti cheating toll algorithm
- · Deployment of toll central control in several highways in China
- · Development of toll line management application
- Data acquisition board design and development for control toll lane devices
- · Embedded toll lane controller development
- · Internal and external training courses

Software Engineer

Mar 1997 - Jan 1998

Responsible for providing development and deployment of applications at the signal analysis application development department.

- Algorithm design for signal analysis in railway maintenance
- Small developments for embedded video surveillance applications



Mar 1996 - Jun 1996

Design, develop and deploy billing application for eletric company.



Jan 1995 - Dec 1995

Teacher in several courses about technical subjects: C, C++, Visual Basic and Wordperfect.



I have taken part in a wide range of projects in different domains during my long professional $\ensuremath{\mathsf{I}}$ career. Here you can find those of them which I feel really proud as top experiences level me up as professional.

Telefonica Kernel - The cross platform of Telefonica which provide authentication, authorization, unified APIs and the algorithm execution environment to generate value for our

4th Platform - The seed from which Telefonica Kernel was born.

TUgo - Telefónica is the first telco in the world to fully launch a browser-based calling product using WebRTC technology.

Jazztel MVNO - Ericsson Multiactivation integration for the Jazztel MVNO. Network provision in HLR / HSS, FNR, MTAS and GGSN core nodes.

Alejandra Portal - TR069 ecosystem full development for the ADSL and FTTH Telefonica's network.

ITS - Small fleets management products, focused in police and public maintenance departments. Central console and embedded software in the remote units.

Free Flow Gate - Toll solutions with automatic vehicle detection for anti cheating purpose. Central console and embedded software in the toll lanes.

VS-DVR-Video surveillance products. Embedded video recorders and transmiters for securityapplications.